Keenan Roe

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate recent UIC graduate majoring in statistics. with 3+ years of professional office experience focusing on self lead projects in sales statistics, logistics, and customer satisfaction. With an ardent interest in statistics, programming, and all around problem solving.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Chicago

Bachelor of Science in Statistics 3.0/3.25

Concentration in Statistical methods and minor in Economics

January 2018 - December 2020

Skills

Several projects and statistical models Written in R and presented for both $\underline{logistic}$ and \underline{linear} $\underline{regression}$.

- · R / R Markdown
- Classification models
- Data Visualization
- · Logistic Regression
- Excel
- · C++
- · Probability distribution
- · Hypothesis testing

- Statistical Theory
- Stochastic modeling
- Predictive modeling
- · Linear Regression
- · Lillear Regression
- Microsoft PPT
- Python
- Confidence intervals

EXPERIENCE

Clariance Spine, 4809 N Ravenswood Ave #119, Chicago IL 60640— Inventory Coordinator

January 2020 - Present

- Suggested and worked on a self guided project to improve sales forecasting using scripting in R and excel
- Organized and streamlined the shipping process improving speed and reducing mistakes
- Diligently tracked inventory across the country communicating with clients and moving inventory ensuring no missed sale

Clariance Spine, 4809 N Ravenswood Ave #119, Chicago IL 60640— Logistics and Warehouse assistant

June 2018 - January 2020

- Assisted in the maintenance and shipment of implants and instruments used in spine surgery
- Worked with a small close team to help clients and tailor their order to the needs of individual doctors
- · Work with an overseas headquarters and managed stock discrepancies

Jewel Osco, 485 Ela Rd, Lake Zurich, IL 60047 — Meat Market Associate

June 2014 - September 2015

- Guided and educated new team members
- Interpreted customer's needs and offered tailored solutions
- Collected, organized, and managed inventory

1907 W Wilson Ave. APT 2B Chicago, IL 60640 **217-220-3097 kroe4@uic.edu**

Major Classes taken

Guided study in Clinical Trials -Worked closely with my professor learning statistical research methods in the medical field and how they apply to clinical trials.

Applied Statistical Models 1 and 2 – delved deep into probability models and regression models

Statistical methods and computingprogramming projects in R and SAS with the goal of improving proficiency at understanding the effect programming has on the data

Probability - Random Variables and Stochastic independence, special distributions, limit theorems.

Statistical Theory - best test, sufficiency, sequential ratio testing, and linear regression

Stochastic Modeling - Markov chains, branching and poisson processes.

Linear Algebra – matrices, matrix transformations eigenvalues and markov chains

References

Marshall Hallas Logistics Manager, Clariance Spine inc. m.hallas@Clariance-spine.us (765)-586-7003

-Marshall has been my supervisor at Clariance for two years. Marshall is whom I worked the most closely with showing off my work ethic and abilities

Sylvain Chambat CEO, Clariance Spine inc. s.chambat@clariance-spine.us (773)-620-2111

-Sylvain is the CEO of Clariance spine. During my three+ years he introduced me to the professional world and provided advice and motivation.

Jennifer Pajda- De La O UIC Professor <u>ipajda2@uic.edu</u> (312)-996-3041

-Jennifer was my professor for applied statistics model 2 and a one on one guided study on clinical trials giving her a good grasp on my academic potential